

Contact Details

Profile

Motivated professional leader with over 20 years of experience in sales and professional development. Hands on how to increase revenue, developed team, identifying markets and areas to focus on, CRM system.

Have been in the position of corporate planning and business development as well as marketing communications & strategy and marketing campaigns programs. Strategical thinking with strong creative and analytical skills. Team player, lead by example with an eye for detail

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Head of Sales and Marketing II Operational Sales II Marketing Strategy II Brand Awareness II Business Develpoment - GROUP COMPANY Sriwijaya Teknik Utama

PT Sriwijaya Teknik Utama Desember 2024 - Present

"The company operates in the field of fabrication- manufacturing for heavy equipment, rotating, engineering equipment and product support in East Kalimantan – Samarinda "

- Responsible for achieving sales targets and revenue, identifying new market opportunities, and developing strategic partnerships in Manufacturing – Fabrication East kalimantan
- Identify new and existing business opportunities to increase the growth of the organisation, promoting strong client engagement, retention and attraction strategies
- To manage daily growth and development of assigned campaigns.
- Develop and manage sales /marketing operating budgets
- Manage Sales canvasser & engineering, Sales counter, Sales Admin: Purchase order, Request of Quotation /RFQ, FIP and hose teams and Marketing Activity and Digital Marketing
- Manage marketing activities that include market research, sales presentations, analysis of sales and marketing trend, advertising and marketing promotional events
- Plan, direct, or coordinate the delivery of a product or service to the customer and Create a Business plan Group Of Company
- Communicate and report effectively to the Chief Executive Officer and the Board.
- Create Work Program , Targeting , Evaluation Monitoring and Budgeting for the Title group of Companies
- CRM Monitoring and controlling to Sales performance and daily activity



EXPERTISE

- LEADERSHIP
- SALES
- MARKETING STRATEGIC
- PROFESIONAL
 COMMUNICATION
- BRAND,
 MARKETING & BD
- ANALITICAL THINKING
- CRM SYSTEM

EDUCATION

- STEI RAMANGUN
 JAKARTA TIMUR
- TRADINGMANAGEMENT
- Periode 1997-2023

Career Break , July 2024 - 30 Nov 2024

- To Explore New Career Opportinities
- During My Career Break, I Pro-actively Invested my time for Participate in Online and Offline workshop activities – Traning Business Skills and Leadership
- On Line Training Is:
 "Business Intellegence Fundamental "By Ronny Kuntur, DrMS. PhD Bya CQU
- Off Line Training Is: "Its Opportunity around you by One of the Founder Prudential by Mr. Gencar Paulus .S .Kom . RFP

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

HEAD OF MARKETING STRATEGY || MARKETING COMMUNICATION || BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT DIVISION

INTRACO PENTA GROUP

January 2018 - Juni 2024

- " Distribution Company sales of heavy equipment, spare parts, business rental for the mining, construction, industry, transportation and agricultural industries " HO-Jakarta Utara
- Leadership & Strategy , Branding , E- Commrce & Digital Marketing, Marketing Communication
- Partnership & Collaborations , Research & Development
- Create Promotion strategy for All 22 Branches of Intraco Penta Group in Indonesia ATL and BTL
- Analyze Marketing Issue Data Customer, marketing Mapping, Campaign Plan & Strategy (SEO,SEM, Social media ,etc)
- focus on marketing activities that have an impact on increasing revenue, Analyze new business and cooperation model development
- Develop and implement a comprehensive branding strategy that aligns with our corporate goals and sets us apart in the Heavy Equipment industry
- Analyses and forms major plans for CRM system to retain loyal members Measure and report



performance of all marketing campaigns

- Lead team of sales and marketing and overseeing their work performance to ensure business achieved
- And was also to temporarily handle Corporate Planning Division too. Periode Oktober 2020 Desember 2022 (2 years)

CORPORATE PLANNING DIVISION

- between other Divison & clients (principals), commercial team operation & related team to drive clients onboarding process faster and further
- Work closely with the CEO & COO to develop business strategy and ensure the alignment with corporate direction (C- Level)
- Build and maintain relationships with key decision-makers to drive sales growth Responsible for CRM as a sales performance tools
- Create Taxonomy for 1 year and Monitoring KPM all Division
- Develop and execute comprehensive strategic plans, to drive business growth and achieve revenue targets Branch/Sales Team
- Coordinate activities and communicate with internal and external partners (Our Principals)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

HEAD OF SALES NATIONAL

(ERAJAYA GROUP)

PT PRIMA PERSONA PRAKASA Okt 2016 - Des 2017

- " Distribution and Retailer of Cellular Communication Products and Services and their maintenance "
- Handling Erajaya's Joint venture business with the largest operator which is Indosat, for a system consignment project in all of indosat's outlet's throughout Indonesia
- Responsible for managing around 160 branches across indonesia
- Ensure sales volume forecasts and profit expectations for existing and new products. Responsible for strategic sales and marketing performance
- Responsible for ATL/BTL marketing Program and Maintenance Budget/ PnL
- Establishes sales objectives, by forecasting and developing annual sales quotas, for regions and territories





PROFESSIONAL EXEPERIENCE

SENIOR REGIONAL SALES MANAGER

PT XL AXIATA Tbk

Jan 2013 - Sept 2016

" PT XL Axiata Tbk is a company operating in the fields of telecommunications, telecommunications networks and multimedia. XL Axiata is one of the leading telecommunications operators in Indonesia."

- Develop business plan & strategic plan to meet the target of company growth B2B – B2C
- My Coverage Jakbodetabek Area, Maintenance Traditional Market/retail – Modern Channel & Device partner
- Manage the day-to-day sales activities in an assigned area (sub-region, country, market segments) in order to implement the organization
- I have to manage almost 2 dealers / Distributor XL, who are responsible for distribute all XL Product
- Analyze the needs of customer in market and managing the cluster /Area
- Responsible to achieve in sales target by executing excellence distribution, implementing merchandising guideline, Leading, coordinating and motivating the Distributor team as well as executing trade promotion program
- Handling Four (4) distributor XL Axiata, and take responsibility for their performance
- Create open booth 4G Corner mini XI Store XL Store In mall & office to Office
- I lead almost 250 sales in the Jabodtebek area, which must be monitored every day.

PROFESSIONAL EXEPERIENCE

SENIOR REGIONAL SALES - YOUTH AND COMMUNITY MANAGER

PT XL AXIATA Tbk

January 2010 - Des 2012

- Create Project market small medium enterprise/SME -Youth & Community and Handling Corporate user Group (CUG) Offering Package data and Voice
- Offering to Corporate With Messaging masking Service for



- Targeted Customer and Offering LBA system and MPLS (list Line) Service XL Corporate with Contract Agreement
- Creating youth community school to school market,
- Alson handling B2B, B2C and B2G Market
- Responsible for increasing continuesly of BTS revenue (Voice, SMS & Mobile data service), cluster capacity & market share with community project
- Manage performance small medium enterprise / SME activity
- Manage performance small medium enterprise / SME activity
- focus on marketing activities that have an impact on increasing revenue
- Responsible for managing all **sales** activities (Including Distributor & DEPO **sales** Operation) to achieve company's targets
- Responsible for increasing continously of BTS Revenue (Voice, SMS & Mobile Data Service), cluster capacity & market share
- Responsible to achieve in sales target by executing excellence distribution, implementing merchandising guideline Leading, coordinating and motivating the distributor team as well as executing trade promotion program

AREA SALES MANAGER PT XL AXIATA Tbk

Jan 2007 - Des 2009

- Responsibilty For Revenue Team Sales Direct Selling -Distributor, especially Retail market and Modern Market
- I have to manage almost 2 dealers / Distributor XL, who are responsible for distribute all XL Product
- Responsible to Achievement for sales target by Excecuting excellence Distribution, implementing merchandise guideline leading, coordinating and motivating the distributors teams as well as executing trade promotion program
- My Experience handling Jakarta and Kalimantan Area Responsible For Increasing BTS Revenue, cluster capacity and market share



PROFESSIONAL EXEPERIENCE

AREA SALES MANAGER

PT AXA MANDIRI FINANCIAL

January 2004 - Des 2006

" AXA Mandiri operates in the fields of life insurance, health insurance and general insurance. AXA Mandiri is a joint venture between PT Bank Mandiri (Persero) Tbk and AXA Group."

- Manage teams financial advisor in branch Bank mandiri
- Responsible Sales in bancassurance production thru Bank and achieve, Experience Handling Jakarta and Kalimantan Area
- Responsible for Mandiri Investment product & Landing Investment product
- Achieve target highest NBC (new business credit) and highest NBI (new business investment), number of million target

ACHIEVEMENT

PT XL AXIATA (Tbk)
Telco / Provider Company

The Best 1st Rank Area Sales Manager Sumatra – Kalimantan - Sulampapua Area - 20018

The Best 2st Rank Area Sales Manager jabodetabek Area 2009 telecommunication

The Best 1st Rank Regional Sales Manager Jabodetabek 2014

The Best Financial Advisor of The Highest AFYP Category, year 2005

The Best 2nd Rank 5 Area Sales Manager for The Highest

The Best Financial Advisor of The Highest NBC Category, year 2005



TRAINING:

- Management and Leadership 2014 PT XL Axiata Tbk
- Sales Skills 2016 PT XL Axiata Tbk
- Leadership Deveopment XL A

